<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>signal processing on Geophydog</title>
    <link>https://geophydog.cool/tags/signal-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in signal processing on Geophydog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Geophydog All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 14:32:30 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://geophydog.cool/tags/signal-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MUltiple SIgnal Classification (MUSIC) Algorithm for Array Processing</title>
      <link>https://geophydog.cool/post/music_array_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 14:32:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geophydog.cool/post/music_array_process/</guid>
      <description>1. MUSIC algorithm The naive beamforming technique, Bartlett beamformer, has a poor resolution although its stability and robustness are good. Schmidt proposed a new beamformer algorithm call multiple signal classification (MUSIC) for addressing the resolution while keeping the stability of beamformer (1986). Here we briefly introduce the MUSIC algorithm and also give some Python codes to show how this technique works.
Assuming a signal $u(t)$ and its Fourier spectrum $U(\omega)$ of a receiver, we have a signal vector of an array composed of $N$ receivers at frequency $\omega$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Stacking: Phase-Weighted Stack (PWS)</title>
      <link>https://geophydog.cool/post/signal_pws_stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 11:17:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geophydog.cool/post/signal_pws_stack/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obtain right Cross-Correlation spectrum</title>
      <link>https://geophydog.cool/post/cross-correlation_spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 15:29:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geophydog.cool/post/cross-correlation_spectrum/</guid>
      <description>1 Background Ambient seismic noise cross-correlation has far-reaching implications for the passive seismic surface wave imaging from regional to continental scales (e.g. Campillo &amp;amp; Paul, Shapiro &amp;amp; Campillo, 2004). Spectral analysis of cross-correlations is the key to retrieving reliable dispersion information about surface waves. Based on the Fourier spectra of event seismic surface wave data, however, we need to shift the cross-correlation time function before doing FFT to obtain the right spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>